Jordan Utz

Front End Software Engineer

Highland Heights, KY

(859) 304-1476

jordanutz@outlook.com

Front-End Software Engineer with **5 years** of professional experience specializing in architecting scalable JavaScript applications using a comprehensive technical skillset guided by knowledge of modern front-end practices pertinent to creating engaging, responsive, and accessible user interfaces.

EXPERIENCE

Kroger Technology & Digital

06/2022 - Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Drove sales through the production and timely release of features designed using React, Typescript, an Redux to power and enhance customers' shopping experiences.
- Supported broader-level initiatives within the organization seeking to maximize profitability through the reduction of technical debt and optimizations to web performance.
- Partnered with stakeholders to accelerate sales through delivered features, ensuring retail divisions achieved desired compliance scores.

WebstaurantStore 05/2020 - 06/2021

Front End Developer

- Collaborated with a team of designers to implement new user interfaces using React.
- Maintained accessibility of the platform to ensure ADA compliance.
- Improved performance of external application tools, significantly reducing build speeds for running and deploying new features.

eLink Design 05/2019 - 04/2020

Web Developer

- Designed and developed responsive, cross-browser-compatible websites.
- Partnered closely with clients, facilitated communication, and promptly implemented feedback to meet appropriate deadlines from initial planning to final product completion.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

Devmountain

BS in Human Nutrition

University of Kentucky

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Git
- Agile
- Responsive Design
- React
- Accessibility
- Redux
- Figma
- Semantic Web Design